Harbir Singh

harbir.us linkedin.com/in/harbir-singh qithub.com/harbir478 Long Beach, CA harbir478@gmail.com (562) 583 7500

Studious web developer with an ability of creating smart solutions in a minimum time. Recently developed a responsive web blog, user-experience survey application, weather forecast, and video automation app.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oditi Global Solutions Pvt. Limited (2013-2015)

Designation: JavaScript Web Developer

- Responsible for development of web-pages of diverse niches to meet customer requirements.
- Perform maintenance updates and adding new features on existing sites.
- Worked with the Senior web developers to manage large and complex clients.
- Contacted clients to discuss requirements and design needs.
- Lead the SEO Team and managed tasks to make search engine friendly websites.

Self-Employed (2010-2013)

Designation: SEO Business using WordPress CMS.

- Attained top position on competitive niche and drove \$400K+ in revenues from organic traffic.
- Build high quality backlinks from the trusted and niche related websites.
- Day to day experimentation for better content placement, user experience, content and bounce rate.
- Knowledge of keyword research tools, website analysis tools and webmaster tools.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript core concepts and DOM manipulation.
- Advance JavaScript libraries & framework like jQuery, Node.js and RESTful routing.
- Passport.js for Token Based (JSON Web Token) and Cookie Based Authentication.
- React.js workflow to build application using React and Redux.
- SASS, CSS5 and Frameworks like Bootstrap, Semantic UI and Materialize CSS.
- Front-end development tools like Webpack, Bebel, NPM and Git Version Control.
- On-Page and off-Page **SEO** techniques, Website analysis, keyword research and mapping.

EDUCATION

Master's in Computer Science from California State University, Long Beach. (2015-2017)

Relevant Coursework Projects

Portfolio – CSS, SASS, HTML5.

<u>Camping Blog</u> - Vanilla JS, Passport.js, Node.js, Express, CSS3, Bootstrap, MongoDB, NPM.

Feedback App - React, Redux, Google OAuth 2.0, ES6, NPM, AXIOS, Heroku, Passport.js.

Crypto-Live Price - ES6, React.js, Redux, CoinMarketCap API.

<u>Video Automator</u> - React, YouTube API, Webpack.

City Weather App – React, Redux, ES6, NPM, Axios